If you want to
grow and make money
from YouTube, the first
thing you need to
do is make sure
the three main parts
of your pipeline are
perfectly aligned. The first
part is your channel,
which drives the traffic
to your marketing. Things
like your email, your
lead magnets, your email
nurture sequences. And the
job of this section
is to keep people
engaged, but also to
introduce them to your
offer. And then your
offer is the final
part, and that is
the thing you actually
sell. When all three
of these are aligned
under your umbrella statement,
the I help X
get Y, your traffic
will flow smoothly between
them. And the people
who go from your
channel to your offer
will be the perfect
fit. And this is
how some people make
like $25 ,000 from
just a few thousand
views. If one of
these stages is misaligned,
which is very easy
to do, the pipe
clogs. So if your
channel doesn't match your
offer and your marketing,
you're going to attract
the wrong people into
it. If your marketing
doesn't match your channel.
Viewers are going to
fill a mismatch and
they're not going to
interact. And if your
offer is misaligned, people
are going to come
to it from your
channel expecting one thing,
but get given presented
something completely different. So
they won't buy. So
any red lights in
this pipeline creates a
huge blockage. And unless
we fix it, your
views can't turn into
income in the way
that you'd want. So
in this video, we're
going to audit your
channel, your marketing and
your offer to see
how they are positioned.
And then we're going
to use guardrails AI
to help spot misalignments.
And then at the
end, I'm going to
show you some tricks.
Guardrails can do once
you've got this all
set up. And then
once you've posted three
or four new videos
using the new system,
we will then measure
their results based on
these adjustments in phase
seven. And then that
will show you exactly
where any bottlenecks might
still remain based on
the new data you've
got following the system.
So how long should
you leave this audit?
Well, it could take
half an hour. It
could take you 10.
It's going to be
different depending on everyone's
situation. But just take
your time here and
follow the steps. Really
was a game changer.
It was a game
changer for me when
I first did this.
OK, so let's move
into step one of
auditing. So here you
want to find the
top three buyer problems.
All right. So why
are we focusing on
buyers, not viewers? Well,
when I first did
this for myself, I
realized that my channel
was targeting different problems
than my buyers cared
about. And when I
switched to make sure
that the channel was
more in line with
what the buyers cared
about, income went up
a lot. And that's
the thing on YouTube.
Not every viewer is
going to be the
perfect fit for you.
In fact, for some
of you. Most of
them probably are. So
we need to optimize
for the people who
actually give us money,
not the people who
don't. But you might
be wondering, hang on
a sec. Why the
top three buyer problems?
Why is this different
between the umbrella statement?
You've got to position
everything around. So think
of it like this.
Your umbrella statement is
like the main storm
you solve. But the
storm isn't necessarily the
problem, right? The problem
you have in a
storm is getting wet.
The wind, the cold,
the puddles. This is
why we want to
work out our buyers
top three problems. Because
those are the problems.
Those are the pain
points they feel. So
for example, if you're
a fitness coach, your
umbrella statement might be,
I help business owners
lose weight with short
workouts. And their top
three problems they know
they have might be,
I don't have time
for long workouts. I
can't stay consistent. I
tried diets, but I
still can't lose weight.
So let's work that
out for ourselves. If
you have clients already,
follow this process. I
want you to collect
data from them. So
hopefully at some point
you've got them to
fill out a form
after they've bought from
you. That says what
their problems are. Or
you might have cool
notes. And if you
do, download them all,
drop them into guardrails
AI and ask audit
my business. And it's
going to pull out
the top three problems
based on that data.
Then you just want
to manually check that.
Now, if you didn't
get your clients to
do that, what I
want you to do
is email everyone who's
ever bought from you
a quick survey that
says something like this.
Hey, name, I want
to help more people.
And then put the
result you want to
help with. Could you
give me 30 seconds
to fill out this
survey? I'll pick one
person who fills it
out and give them
and then insert some
sort of prize. Thank
you very much. Your
name and then link
to a Google form.
And ideally we want
to be getting like
25, 30 plus people
to fill this out.
And if we can
get that, we then
do the same. We
take that data from
the Google forms. We
put it into guardrails
and say, audit my
business. And it's going
to tell you the
top three problems, which
you manually verify. Now,
if you don't have
enough client data, enough
clients, or you can't
do that, don't worry.
Instead, what we're going
to do here is
we're going to. Take
our best educated guess
as to what these
problems might be. And
to help you with
that, just answer these
three questions. What do
people complain about the
most in your niche?
What do they keep
trying but failing to
fix on their own?
What's the number one
frustration or pain point
that's blocking results? And
then take those three
problems and put them
into the brain here
in guardrails. Now, you
can do extra work
on these two. You
could go to Reddit,
Quora. You could look
at YouTube comments to
try and establish these.
But don't overcomplicate right
now. An educated guess
is good enough. We
will build on this
over time. Let me
move on to step
two, where we're going
to check if your
content's actually solving those
same problems too in
the eyes of the
people coming to your
channel. If you've got
an established channel, here's
what I want you
to do. I want
you to pick the
top 12 outliers from
the last two years.
An outlier is simply
a video that performed
at least twice above
your average views. Basically,
you're looking for your
top performers in the
last two years, as
long as they're still
in line with the
direction you want to
take your channel. And
just to be clear,
an established channel isn't
one where you've only
got 20 videos or
one random hit. You've
got a lot of
videos that have hit
55 ,000 views and
the rest have like
500 views. That's not
established. Established means you've
been posting consistently for
a while. You've got
lots of videos pulling
in thousands of views
and you've been hitting
those numbers for a
while. Then what I
want you to do
is take those 12
outliers and write them
on a Google Doc
like this. And then
I want you to
space them out clearly
and then take a
screenshot of that. Make
sure it's just the
titles in the screenshot.
So then once you've
done that, go to
the brain, add it
here and then go
back to Guardrails and
ask, audit my channel.
It's going to give
you the top three
problems it thinks your
viewers care about based
on those outliers. And
the goal here is
really simple. You ask,
do those problems that
is listed line up
with what you believe
your buyers problems are?
Don't panic if they're
a little different. That's
very normal. It only
really becomes a massive
issue if there's a
big mismatch. Now, if
you're not established yet
or you're repositioning your
channel in a completely
new direction, just skip
that step for now.
We're going to come
back to it in
phase four. And don't
stress if you can't
fill it out. It
doesn't mean this course
doesn't work for you
at all. Still the
perfect. We're just going
to update this later.
One other thing I
might add is for
me, my list of
12 outliers were not
just views based because
I have rev track.
I can see which
videos generate the most
sales and email signups.
So my list is
a mixture of videos
that perform well for
the business and for
views. Then step three,
we're going to audit
your offer. So all
you do is you
go to your sales
page, drag your mouse
down it, copy all
the text, paste all
the text into Guardrails
and say, audit my
sales page and then
write down your score.
If you don't have
a sales page, don't
worry. Move on. Step
four, we're then going
to audit your marketing.
So you're going to
go to your email
signup or your lead
magnet signup, and you're
going to copy the
text in the same
way, paste it into
Guardrails and then write
audit my email signup
page and then write
down your score. And
in step five, all
we're going to do
is spot the red
light, look at the
score and any advice
it might give and
ask, oh, do we
have a problem there
or not? But here's
something you need to
understand. AI is not
perfect. This is a
tool. It's version one
of the tool as
well. So I'll be
improving it over time.
But you still have
a brain. So just
don't treat this as
gospel. The real value
of all this information
is it explains things
quite clearly to you.
So it's going to
help you spot problems
for yourself. This is
also the part that
generally requires the most
support questions to be
asked. So if you're
like, this is hard
to figure out for
myself, the positioning, all
this stuff. Don't be
a stranger in the
chat members. OK, so
now we've got the
minimum part of our
brain set up. Let
me show you what
it can do once
it's fully set up.
So the whole point
of filling out the
brain here with your
positioning statement, your buyer
problems and eventually the
other data you're going
to see is that
later in the course,
I can use it
like this so I
could take a random
intro that has nothing
to do with the
positioning of my channel,
I can drop it
into guardrails and it
instantly rewrites it so
it's aligned with my
umbrella statement and the
top three problems my
buyers care about. Can
you see the difference
there? It literally makes
sure we always relate
everything back to the
thing our dream buyers
care about. And this
is what makes it
so powerful and what
will make your content
stick out more than
anyone else's because the
viewers are going to
go, wow, this person
flipping gets me. But
we can also put
in an idea and
just say, what do
you think of this
idea? And it's going
to say this is
poorly aligned with what
your buyers care about.
It might say this
is perfect. We can
throw in a title
and it's going to
say this is a
great title or a
bad title. And it's
going to give you
some other suggestions. Now,
what you need to
be careful with is
don't just go using
the titles. This is
not the ultimate title
bot. It's just there
for inspiration or use
weird words. You will
learn how to do
titles properly in phase
four when we do
the strategy. But the
real goal here is
over the next six
to 18 months, what
we want to do
is test fail as
fast as we can
and learn as much
about our buyers as
we possibly can. And
then you just keep
updating this problem list
inside the brain. You
update your outliers. Even
your positioning statement can
get updated. And then
each update will make
this thing smarter and
more like your dream
buyer, because that's what
this is. We're basically
creating your dream buyer
to give feedback on
everything you make so
that it optimises it
for them, nobody else.
Honestly, this is one
of the most powerful
tools I've ever used
for YouTube. I use
it every flipping day.
I'm very excited for
you to have it
too. Now, moving to
the next video, we're
just going to make
some small adjustments to
anything that you've discovered
here following a slightly
different process.